Jobs to be done is another tool that you
need to to know of. It's an approach
developing products by looking at the
jobs of the customer and the processes
that would lead that customers to hire a
product to do the job.
So,
why I
tell you about this is that we usually
look at how the current state in the
users life is, how things are.
Um, what's the outcome? The outcome is
them using our product. Love it. But,
what is the progress towards there?
Because if the progress is super hard,
then they won't make the change and use
your product. So, you need to take care
of this jobs to be done and know about
them because usually the process of them
actually getting to use your product is
more important
and more lengthy and it's a cost that
they won't don't want to pay. So, maybe
that is why they won't use your product
even though yes, it would be useful. You
should build first your problem
statements. So, I kept saying problem
space and so on. Usually, this is how
you start with a problem and if you
cannot emphasize your problem in a
problem statement template, it's a
problem. Who
who has the problem? What is the
problem? When does it occur and why?
So,
when we look at the why, we look at how
big the problem is for the user because
there are some small some small problems
that I would never pay to get solved.
So,
you need to address the problems that
are most painful.
When? If it happens once a year, I won't
pay for it. Maybe I need to do it only
once a year. So, therefore, why pay for
it?
And what and who you already know.